[
    {
    "question":"C99 standard guarantees uniqueness of  ___________ characters for internal names.",
    "optionA":"31",
    "optionB":"63",
    "optionC":"12",
    "optionD":"14",
    "answer":"63"
    },

    {
        "question": "Which of the following is true for variable names in C?",
        "optionA": "They can contain alphanumeric characters as well as special characters",
        "optionB": "Variable names cannot start with a digit",
        "optionC": "It is not an error to declare a variable to be one of the keywords",
        "optionD": "Variable can be of any length",
        "answer": "Variable names cannot start with a digit"
    },

    {
        "question": "Which data type is most suitable for storing a number 65000 in a 32-bit system? ",
        "optionA": "signed short",
        "optionB": "unsigned short",
        "optionC": "long",
        "optionD": "int",
        "answer": "unsigned short"
    },

    {
        "question": "For which of the following, 'PI++;' code will fail? ",
        "optionA": "#define PI 3.14",
        "optionB": "char *PI = 'A'; ",
        "optionC": "float PI = 3.14; ",
        "optionD": "None of the above",
        "answer":  "#define PI 3.14"
    },

    {
        "question": "enum types are processed by ",
        "optionA": "Complier",
        "optionB": "Preprocessor",
        "optionC": "Linker",
        "optionD": "Assembler",
        "answer": "Complier"
    },

    {
        "question": "Which of the following is not a pointer declaration?",
        "optionA": "char a[10]; ",
        "optionB": "char a[] = {'1' , '2' , '3' , '4' };",
        "optionC": "char *str;",
        "optionD": "char a;",
        "answer": "char a;"
    },

    {
        "question": "When double is converted to float, then the value is ?",
        "optionA": "Truncated",
        "optionB": "Rounded",
        "optionC": "Depends on the complier",
        "optionD": "Depends on the standard",
        "answer": "Depends on the complier"
    },

    {
        "question": "What will be value of the following assignment expression?",
        "question1":" (X = foo())!= 1 considering foo() return 2",
        "optionA": "2",
        "optionB": "True",
        "optionC": "1",
        "optionD": "0",
        "answer": "2"
    },
    

    {
        "question": "In expression i = g() + f(), first function called depends on _________ ",
        "optionA": "Complier",
        "optionB": "Associativity of() operator",
        "optionC": "Precedence of () and + operator",
        "optionD": "Left to write of the expression",
        "answer":  "Complier"
    },
    
    {
        "question": "Which of the following option is the correct representation of the following C statement?",
        "question1":" e = a * b + c / d * f;",
        "optionA": "e = (a * (b +(c /(d * f))));",
        "optionB": "e = ((a * b) + (c / (d * f)));",
        "optionC": "e = ((a * b) + ((c / d)* f));",
        "optionD": "Both B and C",
        "answer":  "both B and C"
    }

  
]